Antonio Ercole De Luca

Senior Software Engineer Bayesian Machine Learning Engineer

SKILLS

- Python
- SQL
- **Pandas**
- Django
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- **AWS**
- Google Cloud
- Selenium
- Bayesian Inference
- **FBprophet**
- Dask
- Optuna
- Scrum
- TDD

LANGUAGES

- Italian
- English
- Spanish

CONTACT



- E-mail: eracle@posteo.eu
- · Personal web site: https://eracle.me

PROFILE

I am a Senior Software Engineer, working as a consultant since 2016, having shifted over different roles such as Machine Learning Engineer, Data Architect, Data Scientist, DevOps, and Scrum Master.

I have worked on all aspects of data management such as retrieval, storage, cloud infrastructure scaling, data analysis, and mining; encompassing web scraping, design of relational databases, cloud deployment, RESTful API, and Jupiter

In 2019 I took a couple of sabbatical years to get into the world of Statistics &

During my career, I also contributed to two scientific papers in the field of Web Scraping and Data Visualization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Consultant, Remote (2017 - 2019)

Data Architect

Worked with more than 10 international clients on Upwork.com receiving 5/5 stars as median feedback

Some stories:

- Designed an image similarity search engine with near zero response time, indexing more than 40 000 imgs by using Approximate Nearest Neighbors data structure;
- Reduced client's cloud infrastructure costs by dockerizing a diango app and migrating from Digital Ocean to Google Cloud;
- Built a django app with 83% testing coverage by using Test Driven Development.

Legalkite Ltd, Zurich (2016 - 2017)

Back-end Software Engineer

Design of several RESTful endpoints;

Improved 10x REST API response time by translating django ORM queries into raw SQL queries;

Solved data inconsistency bugs by:

- Refactoring postgres schema;
- Making Elasticsearch a read-replica:

Scaled 100x scraping module by porting it to scrapy and scrapinghub.

SpazioDati, Pisa, Italy (2015-2016)

Machine Learning Engineer

Design of a Human-in-the-loop Active Learning workflow using CrowdFlower API (now Appen). Increased 2x F1-score in Logistic Regression model used for Named Entity Linking by using Uncertainty Sampling.

Synthema, Pisa, Italy (2014-2015)

Software Developer

Productionize Natural Language Processing steps: Segmentation, Tokenization, POS, Stop Words, Dep.Parsing, NER; (Romanian, Japanese, Chinese and German) EU funded (5.6 Mln €) project: CAPER.

EDUCATION

Bachelors Degree

Statistics & Data Science Università di Palermo, Italy

Financial Mathematics, Finance Theory, Multivariate Analysis, Inference, R Language, Probability.

Masters Degree

(2011 - 2013)

(2019 - 2020)

Data Science and Business Informatics

University of Pisa, Italy

Thesis on Natural Language Processing:

Applying Active Learning on Entity Linking.

Bachelors Degree

(2007 - 2010)

Computer Science

University of Pisa, Italy

Thesis on Natural Language Processing:

Document classification using lexical and semantic resources.